Previously on Transformers: Prime
在上一集里
Bravo, Optimus!
干得漂亮 擎天柱！
You may wish to save your strength for the main event!
你最好为正戏保存一点实力！
We need to find Fowler and get these kids outta here.
我们得找到福勒 再把孩子们带出去
It's your fault that we're stuck in this intensity.
我们被卷进来 都是因为你
What were you thinking, Miko?
你是怎么想的 神子？
I know math when I see it.
我一看就知道那是数学问题
And that is one serious equation.
那可是个信息量巨大的方程式
If this was just an average day with the Autobots,
如果和汽车人在一起 每天都有生命危险
then I don't wanna be a part of it.
那我不干了
Your mindless agenda resulted in the disabling of my ship!
可你干的蠢事弄垮了我的飞船！
And the delay of my plans!
还耽误了我的大事！
Megatron's building a Space Bridge
威震天正在建造太空桥
to bring through his conquering army.
用它召集一支征服大军
But the only place Megatron could recruit that many fallen warriors...
可是 唯一能让威震天召唤无数死人的地方是…
Cybertron.
塞博特恩
We cannot allow Megatron to send Dark Energon through his Space Bridge.
绝不能让威震天用他的太空桥传送黑暗能量
If we fail,
如果我们失败了
the dead of Cybertron will rise,
塞博特恩的死者们将会复活
swarm through his vortex,
冲破他的时空漩涡
and invade Earth,
并侵略地球
bending human kind to Megatron's twisted rule.
人类将在威震天的邪恶统治下痛不欲生
Nice bike.
单车不错嘛
Arcee, really, Miko already tried.
阿尔茜 说真的 神子已经和我谈过了
Tell Optimus I respect him big time. But...
告诉擎天柱 我非常敬重他 但…
if you're at war with the Decepticons,
如果你们跟霸天虎交战的话
there's nothing I can do to help.
我也帮不上什么忙
Optimus didn't send me, and no one's asking for your help.
不是擎天柱派我来的 也没人请你帮忙
Ok, so if we both agree that I'm not warrior material...
好吧 既然你我都知道 我不是打仗的料…
Jack, I just lost someone I cared about.
杰克 我刚失去了一个知心朋友
Maybe it's the grief talking...
可能是出于悲痛…
maybe you're growing on me.
也可能是和你投缘
Whatever it is, I'm just not ready to say good-bye.
无论怎样 我还不想说再见
Optimus, I've pinpointed the location of Megatron's Space Bridge.
擎天柱 我找到威震天那个太空桥的方位了
High in Earth's orbit.
在地球轨道的最高点上
Out of our reach.
超出了我们的行动范围
Ok, so you guys don't fly.
好吧 就算你们不能飞
But can't you just Ground Bridge there?
那么用环陆桥不就行了吗？
A Ground Bridge has limited range.
环陆桥的传输范围是有限的
Stretch all the way into the orbited vortex could snap
冲进环轨道运行的时空漩涡
and scatter us to the stars.
可能会把我们弹射到宇宙的任何地方
Since Megatron is likely already in transit,
威震天应该已经在招兵买马了
I'm afraid we must take that risk.
恐怕我们要硬闯虎穴
Reaching the Space Bridge first, is our only means of stopping him.
要想制止他 我们只有到太空桥上殊死一搏了
Hey, guess who's back.
嘿 猜猜谁回来了
Autobots, prepare for departure.
汽车人 准备出发
Where to?
去哪儿？
The final frontier.
“最后的边疆”（《星际迷航》台词）
Space? I... I thought they didn't have any way to get there.
太空？我还以为他们没法上天呢
They don't,
他们不能
really.
的确不能
Be careful, Bee.
小心点儿 大黄蜂
I'm so jealous.
我真是眼红
Don't even think about following me.
甭想找借口跟着我
Optimus, if you leave me stranded on a planet teeming with humans,
擎天柱 如果你把我永远丢在这个只有人类的星球上
I will never forgive you.
我决不会原谅你
Until we meet again, old friend.
后会有期 老朋友
Autobots, roll out!
汽车人 出发！
Maximum overdrive!
全速前进！
Autobots, transform
汽车人 变形！
and gravitise!
着陆！
Don't look down, or up, or left.
别往下看 别往上看 别往左看
So Megatron's packing enough Dark Energon to raise Cybertron's dead?
这么说 威震天准备了足够的黑暗能量 足以让塞博特恩的死者全都复活？
And since we don't possess ready means of disabling the Space Bridge,
既然我们没有十足的把握关闭太空桥
nothing gets in or out.
那就谁也休想从这儿进出！
Unlike you, Starscream!
不像你 红蜘蛛！
No need for concern, master.
不必担心 主人
Soundwave is locking on to Cybertron's coordinates
声波正在锁定塞博特恩的坐标
per my instructions.
是我让他去做的
Well, what are they waiting for?
那个…他们还在等什么？
It appears that the Decepticons have sustained serious damage to their inter-stellar navigation system.
看来霸天虎飞船的星际导航系统出现了严重的损坏
Oh, that's my handy work.
噢 那是我干的
Great job, Bulkhead.
做得好 隔板
Without the dish,
没有天线
Megatron will be unable to aim the Space Bridge at Cybertron.
威震天就无法让太空桥和塞博特恩对接
Don't the Decepticons know where their own planet is?
霸天虎连自己的星球都找不到吗？
Naturally,
当然能
but Cybertron is many light years away.
但塞博特恩位于数万光年以外
To reach their target, their aim must be astronomically precise.
要想连接目的地 他们的定位必须无比精准
If Megatron went to the trouble of rendezvousing with his Space Bridge,
如果威震天在和太空桥接轨时出了问题
He must have an alternate targeting system.
他必然会借助于另一个定位系统
A remote one.
一个远距离系统
From what I know of Earth technology,
哼 根据我对地球科技的了解
I doubt there would exist a single radio telescope dish on this planet
这个星球上没有一个射电望远镜天线
powerful enough to pinpoint Cybertron.
功率大到可以锁定塞博特恩
What about a whole bunch of linked radio telescope dishes?
如果用射电望远镜天线阵列呢
Like the giant size array in Texas?
比如说德克萨斯州的那个阵列？
Sit back... this is not a child's play.
老实呆着…这可不是在过家家
Good thinking, Raf.
好主意 拉夫
Ratchet, have Agent Fowler alert the array's stuff to the security hazard.
救护车 让福勒探员通知阵列的工作人员 提高警惕
You, soldier,
你 大兵！
you're out of uniform. Put on some pants.
你没穿制服 把裤子穿上！
That maybe a challenge.
这恐怕难度不小
I can't get passed the array's firewalls.
我没法入侵阵列的防火墙
They're too thick.
安全系数太高了
You... actually think you could keep the Decepticons out?
你…以为自己能挡得住那些霸天虎吗？
Maybe... if I could get in.
只要能…入侵系统的话…
Wait, wait, wait. Raf.
等等 拉夫
What if we could get you... all the way in? Like "inside the building" in?
我们把你送到…最里边怎么样？ 也就是说“建筑内部”？
I can login to their internal network on the other side of the firewall.
我可以在防火墙的另一端登录他们的内部网络
The risk is too great.
这样太冒险了
The Decepticons will be there. Perhaps even on site.
霸天虎也会去那儿的 很可能现在就到了
Optimus, with all due respect,
擎天柱 恕我直言
you said that yourself,
你自己说过
this is bigger than the safety of three humans.
这远比三个地球人的安危更重要
Yeah, if we let the Cons win,
是啊 如果让虎子们赢了
we're fragged along with everyone else on our planet.
我们会和地球上所有的人一起遭殃
Raf?
拉夫？
I want to give it a shot.
我想试试看
Surely, Lord Megatron,
我敢肯定 威震天陛下
the Autobots are up to something.
汽车人想搞破坏
Really, Starscream?
真的吗 红蜘蛛？
Crush them!
干掉他们！
Here comes the welcoming committee.
大队人马前来迎驾了
- That'll take some getting used to. - Wow...
- 还得适应一阵子 - 喔…
Security sure is lack in this place.
这里的安全系统太差劲了
I'm in...
我进入系统了…
and so are the Decepticons.
可这好像是霸天虎的系统
What?
什么？
How can you tell?
你怎么知道？
Schematics, with the same alien math we saw on their ship.
看这些图表 外星方程式和他们船上的一样
But this time, I can download it.
但这次 我能下载了
It's got to be the Space Bridge.
一定是太空桥
The Decepticons are synching it to the dishes.
霸天虎在把它和天线同步
But I can synch to them.
但我也能如法炮制
Will they know?
他们会发现吗？
Even if the Decepticons see that I'm in the system,
就算霸天虎发现我入侵了系统
they'll have no idea I'm in the house.
也想不到我就在这间屋子里
What just happened?
这是怎么回事？
The Decepticons are locking on to Cybertron.
霸天虎正在锁定塞博特恩
Lord Megatron, the Space Bridge is ready for activation.
威震天陛下 太空桥随时可以启动
Finally!
总算好了！
They're locked on to Cybertron, but not for long.
他们要锁定塞博特恩 别高兴得太早
Indeed, Bumblebee,
没错 大黄蜂
this can only be Raf's doing.
这一定是拉夫干的
Starscream, what is happening?
红蜘蛛！什么情况？
Soundwave, what is happening?
声波！什么情况？
The dishes are heading back towards Cybertron.
天线又转向塞博特恩了
I'll just undo that again.
我让它们再转回来
What happens when the Cons realize to being punked?
万一虎子们知道被耍了 怎么办？
It's only virtual combat.
这只是虚拟战斗
You know, like online gaming.
就像在线游戏一样
Yeah, Jack, what are the Cons gonna do?
是啊 杰克 虎子们还能怎么办？
They're probably like a thousand miles away.
他们很可能远在千里之外呢
I won't let them lock on again.
我不会再让他们锁定了
You handed in an axe?!
你送给他一把斧头？！
Not good.
惨了！
Why's he leaving?
他怎么走了？
He cut the hard line.
他把主线切断了
The dishes are locked on to Cybertron...
天线已经被锁定在塞博特恩了…
for good.
永久地
Now, Starscream.
开始吧 红蜘蛛
Now.
开始
At last!
最后一搏！
Arise, my legion!
觉醒吧 我的军团！
So, how do we beat a whole planet of the undead?
那个…我们如何击败整个星球的活死人？
Optimus,
擎天柱
I'm registering a rapidly expanding mass in their Space Bridge vortex,
他们的太空桥漩涡里出现一股能量 而且在迅速增强
one with a peculiar energy signature.
能量特征非常诡异
Dark Energon.
黑暗能量
Ratchet, we must destroy the Space Bridge.
救护车 我们必须摧毁太空桥
There's enough live energon coursing through it, to achieve detonation.
现在通过漩涡的生命能量足够多 可以实施爆破
But we lack the fire power to ignite it.
但我们的火力还不足以引爆它
If I knew how the Space Bridge was engineered,
如果我知道太空桥的工程原理
I might find a technical way of accomplishing at feet.
也许能从技术上找到突破口
Umm, will schematics help?
呃 用图表可以吗？
Optimus, I must say,
擎天柱 我必须提醒你
the Space Bridge is our sole hope of ever returning to Cybertron.
太空桥是我们返回塞博特恩的唯一希望
Are you certain its destruction is the only option?
你确定摧毁它是唯一的选择吗？
I am afraid so.
恐怕是的
Then by all means,
那就全力以赴吧
let us light our darkest hour!
让我们照亮这最黑暗的时刻吧！
Autobots, take your positions,
汽车人 各就各位
and follow Ratchet's lead.
听救护车指挥
While I make my stand.
这里就交给我了
Your fellow Autobots are wise, Optimus.
你的汽车人伙伴还算识时务 擎天柱
They know when to retreat.
他们知道什么时候应该撤退
I hold no illusions about engaging your army, Megatron.
我没打算跟你整支军团硬拼 威震天
But I might derail its objective...
但我会让他们溃不成军…
by removing its head.
我要擒贼先擒王！
Highly and likely Optimus,
完全赞同 擎天柱
as I am infused with their very might!
因为强大的力量已集我于一身！
One shall stand, one shall fall!
不是你死 就是我亡！
These things are getting closer.
那些东西越来越近了
That's bad, right?
情况不妙 对吧？
Ratchet, we're in position.
救护车 我们已经就位
Arcee, pay close attention.
阿尔茜 仔细看好
Master?
主人？
Starscream, what is it?!
红蜘蛛 又怎么了？
I do not wish to question your all-seeing wisdom,
我不想质疑您运筹帷幄的智慧
but I believe the Autobots are up to something again.
但我认为 汽车人又在捣鬼
Beneath your bridge, this time.
这次是在您的桥下
Uh, misdirection, Optimus?
声东击西啊 擎天柱
You would have made a fine Decepticon!
你做霸天虎一定出类拔萃！
I chose my side!
我已经选择了阵营！
Starscream, my army approaches.
红蜘蛛 我的军队已经接近了
Rendezvous with the Space Bridge for pickup!
到太空桥会合 准备接应！
Now follow the line from the flow regulator to the energon pump.
沿着流量调节器的线路走到能量泵
There should be a valve.
那里应该有个阀门
I see it.
我看到了
Good. To turn all that power against itself,
好 让它用自己的能量进行爆破
all you need do is reverse the current.
你只需要改变电流的方向
Current reversed.
电流转向完成
Yes!
太好了！
Right?
没错吧？
I'll ready the Ground Bridge.
我去准备环陆桥
Starscream! Where is my ship?
红蜘蛛！我的飞船在哪儿？
We would never make it, Lord Megatron!
我们顶不住了 威震天陛下
Don't be a fool! Take flight and retreat!
别犯傻了 上船撤退吧！
Optimus, the Ground Bridge is ready and waiting!
擎天柱 环陆桥已经准备就绪！
Autobots, jump!
汽车人 跳桥！
My legion!
我的军团啊…
No!
不！
Decepticons, it is with deep sorrow
霸天虎们 我怀着沉痛的心情
that I note for the log...
向大家宣告…
Megatron's spark has been extinguished.
威震天的火种已经熄灭了
All... hail... Starscream!
红蜘蛛…万…岁！
Do you... think they're...
你觉得…他们…
Four life signals.
四个生命信号
One very faint.
有一个非常微弱
Bulkhead!
隔板！
We lost one this week,
这周我们已经失去了一个
by the Allspark, don't let it be two.
看在火种源的份上 别再上演悲剧了
Arcee...
阿尔茜…
Jack, really?
杰克 不用伤心吧？
There are other motorcycles in the world.
世界上有的是摩托车
But you're my first.
可你是我的第一辆
And Megatron?
威震天怎么了？
Not even he could've survived Ground Zero.
就算他也绝不可能在爆炸中心幸存
Prime!
擎天柱！
I didn't get to thank you, but for the save,
我还没谢过你 但你们救了我
I owe you one.
算我欠你的
We all do.
全人类欠你们的
So, is this the part where you say good-bye
那么 现在是不是该说再见了
and tell us we need to forget we ever saw you?
要我们忘记曾经见过你们吗？
Without the means of leaving this world,
现在我们已经无法离开这个世界了
we Autobots take strength in the bonds we have forged with our three young friends.
但汽车人与三个年轻的朋友建立了友谊 并从中得到力量
True warriors,
他们是真正的勇士
if not in body,
虽然身体弱小
then in spirit.
但拥有坚强的意志
My name is Optimus Prime.
我的名字是擎天柱
And I send this message:
我发出这条信息：
Though we did no choose to be of earth,
虽然留在地球并非我们所选
it would seem that we are here to stay.
但既来之 则安之
If you approach this planet with hostile intent,
如果有人怀着敌意前来进犯
know this:
请记住：
we will defend ourselves,
我们会保卫自己
we will defend humanity.
我们会保卫人类
We will defend our home.
我们会保卫我们共同的家园